royalcaribbeanblog.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy | Royal Caribbean Blog

ROYALCARRIBEANBLOG.COM  
PRIVACY POLICY  
Last Updated: January 2, 2019

This privacy policy (“Policy”) describes how Royalcarribeanblog.com, a website operated by Regal Sea Media LLC, (the “Blog”) collects, uses and shares personal information of consumer users of this website, RoyalCarribeanBlog.com (the “Site”). This Policy also applies to any of our other websites that post this Policy. This Policy does not apply to websites that post different statements.

### WHAT WE COLLECT

 **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.

 **Contact Data** includes email address.

 **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website. 

 **Profile Data** includes your username and password, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.  

 **Usage Data** includes[information about how you use our website, products and services. 

We get information about you in a range of ways. 

 **Information You Give Us**. We collect information you directly give us on our Site.

 **Information We Get From Others**. We may get information about you from other sources. We may add this to information we get from this Site.

 **Information Automatically Collected**. We automatically log information about you and your computer. For example, when visiting our Site, we log your computer operating system type, browser type, browser language, the website you visited before browsing to our Site, pages you viewed, how long you spent on a page, access times and information about your use of and actions on our Site. 

 **Cookies**. We may log information using "cookies." Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site.    This type of information is collected to make the Site more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs.

The Site is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

### USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use your personal information as follows:

  * We use your personal information to operate, maintain, and improve our sites, products, and services.
  * We use your personal information to process and deliver contest entries and rewards.
  * We use your personal information to respond to comments and questions and provide customer service.
  * We use your personal information to send information including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages.
  * We use your personal information to communicate about promotions, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by us and our selected partners.
  * We use your personal information to link or combine user information with other personal information.
  * We use your personal information to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.
  * We use your personal information to provide and deliver products and services customers request.

### SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share personal information as follows:

  * We may share personal information with your consent. For example, you may let us share personal information with others for their own marketing uses. Those uses will be subject to their privacy policies.
  * We may share personal information when we do a business deal, or negotiate a business deal, involving the sale or transfer of all or a part of our business or assets. These deals can include any merger, financing, acquisition, or bankruptcy transaction or proceeding.
  * We may share personal information for legal, protection, and safety purposes.
    * We may share information to comply with laws.
    * We may share information to respond to lawful requests and legal processes.
    * We may share information to protect the rights and property of Royalcarribeanblog.com, our agents, customers, and others. This includes enforcing our agreements, policies, and terms of use.
    * We may share information in an emergency. This includes protecting the safety of our employees and agents, our customers, or any person.
  * We may share information with those who need it to do work for us.

We may also share aggregated and/or anonymized data with others for their own uses.

### INFORMATION CHOICES AND CHANGES

Our marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out.” If you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you.

You may send requests about personal information to our Contact Information below. You can request to change contact choices, opt-out of our sharing with others, and update your personal information.

You can typically remove and reject cookies from our Site with your browser settings. Many browsers are set to accept cookies until you change your settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it could affect how our Site works for you. 

### For Residents of the European Union (“EU”) – General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)

This Privacy Policy describes how the Blog collects, uses and shares your personal information. If you are a resident of the EU, you are subject to the GDPR, which becomes effective on May 25, 2018, and the following terms also apply to you. The Blog is the Controller and responsible for your personal data.

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manage] using the details set out below. 

### Lawful Bases to Process Your Personal Data 

This Privacy Policy describes the personal data we collect from you and how we use it. We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by [contacting us](mailto:matt@royalcaribbeanblog.com?subject=Contact%20Us). Specifically, we have a lawful basis for processing each type of personal data described in this Privacy Policy, which are as follows:

1\. The lawful basis for collecting your Identity and Contact Data to register you as a new customer is the performance of a contract with you.  
2\. The lawful bases for collecting your Identity, Contact, Profile, and Marketing and Communications Data to manage a relationship with you are (a) the performance of a contract with you and (b) it is necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services).  
3\. The lawful bases for collecting your Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, and Marketing and Communications Data to enable you to partake in a contest, competition or complete a survey are (a) the performance of a contract with you and (b) it is necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products and services, to develop them and grow our business).  
4\. The lawful basis to collect your Identity, Contact, and Technical Data to administer and protect our business and the Service is that it is necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganization or group restructuring exercise).  
5\. The lawful basis to collect your Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, Marketing and Communications, and Technical Data to deliver relevant Service content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you is that it is necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy).  
6\. The lawful basis to collect Technical and Usage Data to use data analytics to improve our Service, marketing, customer relationships and experiences is that it is necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our Service updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy).  
7\. The lawful basis to collect Identity, Contact, Profile, Usage, and Technical Data to make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you is that it is necessary for legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business).

We do not collect any Special Categories of personal data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offenses.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out forth in this Privacy Policy. 

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes described in this Policy.

### External Third Parties

  * Service providers (acting as processors) based in the United States who provide IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers [acting as processors or joint controllers] including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the United States who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * Travel agencies who may collect personal information in order to provide a quote for travel.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy. 

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### International Processing

We are based in the United States, which is where all your data will be processed.

### Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.  We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

#### Data Retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data. In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

### YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS UNDER THE GDPR

Under certain circumstances, EU residents have rights under data protection laws in relation to their personal data. If you are an EU resident, you have the right to:

  *  **Request access to your personal data**. This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  *  **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  *  **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 
  *  **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  *  **Request restriction** of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 
  *  **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 
  *  **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us. You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

 **CONTACT INFORMATION**. We welcome your comments or questions about this privacy policy. You may also contact us at our address:

Regal Sea Media LLC  
6222 Lewis and Clark Ave  
Winter Garden, Florida 34787  

 **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**. We may change this privacy policy. If we make any changes, we will change the Last Updated date above.
